Guide to the Herman W. Liebert Manuscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Herman W. Liebert manuscript collection
1604-1987
GEN MSS 237
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.8
(6 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
The Liebert Autograph Collection contains chiefly British (as well as other European and American) historical and literary manuscripts and autographs, including items by James Boswell, Jr., Sir Joseph Banks, Marie Corelli, Eugene V. Debs, Camille Pissarro, Jean-Jacques Rousseau, Thomas Henry Huxley, Samuel Johnson, Ouida, and Alfred Tennyson. The Liebert Correspondence consists of letters written to Liebert by Ian Fleming, Beverly Nichols, John Cowper Powys, and Thornton Wilder.
Liebert, Herman W.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Herman W. Liebert and the Liebert Estate, 1953-1984, including manuscripts given in honor of Liebert by his children, Frederick P. Liebert and Lucy B. Liebert in 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
HERMAN W. LIEBERT (1911-1994)
Herman Wardwell ("Fritz") Liebert, Yale Class of 1933, was a bibliophile, literary scholar and collector, the author of several works about Samuel Johnson, and the first Librarian of The Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Many of the literary and historical manuscripts he acquired personally over the years he eventually gave to the Yale Library. During his tenure as Librarian of The Beinecke Library (1963-1972), he also was actively involved in the direct acquisition of materials for the library's collections.
For additional information, see the numerous references to Herman W. Liebert in the index to The Yale University Library Gazette, and memorials written at the time of his death and printed in the Gazette, Vol. 70, Numbers 1-2 (October 1995).
Scope and Contents
The Herman W. Liebert Manuscript Collection includes many of the historical and literary manuscripts that Liebert acquired for his personal collection and gave singly or in groups to the library, as well as a small body of his personal correspondence with prominent individuals. (However, Mr. Liebert's many gifts of manuscripts and other material pertaining to the English poet and essayist, Austin Dobson, are housed and described separately as the Herman W. Liebert Collection of Austin Dobson.) The collection also incorporates a group of manuscripts purchased by the library in 1995 from the Liebert estate, and two works by Max Beerbohm (folders 8-9) believed to have been part of Mr. Liebert's collection, which were given to the library in 1995 by his children, Frederick P. Liebert and Lucy B. Liebert, in memory of their father. Other caches of Liebert gifts remain in previously cataloged collections.
The Collection is arranged into two principal series. Series I, Liebert Autograph Collection (1604-1987), contains chiefly British, as well as other European and American historical and literary manuscripts and autographs. Individuals represented in the files include: James Boswell, Jr., Sir Joseph Banks, Marie Corelli, Eugene V. Debs, Camille Pissarro, Jean-Jacques Rousseau, Thomas Henry Huxley, Samuel Johnson, Ouida, and Alfred Tennyson. With the exception of the Martin Farquhar Tupper manuscripts and letters (folders 154-174), individuals are represented by fewer than five manuscripts, and in many cases by only one. The list for Series I also includes cross references to additions since 1996 that are housed in Series III.
Series II, Liebert Correspondence (1948-1967), consists of a handful of letters written to Liebert by persons of note, which he gave to the library for their association and autograph value.
Series III, Additions Since 1996, houses manuscripts that were previously cataloged and filed separately, but which have now been reunited with the other Liebert manuscripts. Cross references have been made in Series I and II for items housed in Series III.
Within each series, materials are arranged in alphabetical order by the author of the document. Items of unidentified authorship in Series I are listed at the end of that section. Oversize material has been housed separately and cross references have been made in the appropriate series.
Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting; Poetry; Scrapbooks; Edward, King of Great Britain, VII, 1841-1910; Ouida, 1839-1908; Pius, Pope, IX, 1792-1878; Anstey, F., 1856-1934; Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820; Baretti, Giuseppe, 1719-1789; Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956; Boswell, James, 1778-1822; Browning, Robert, 1812-1889; Bruce, James, 1730-1794; Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849-1924; Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879; Chalmers, Alexander, 1759-1834; Colbert, Jean Baptiste, 1619-1683; Colvin, Sidney, 1845-1927; Cooke, Thomas, 1703-1756; Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924; Crabbe, George, 1754-1832; Crane, Walter, 1845-1915; Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878; Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811; Davies, Thomas, 1713-1785; Davy, Humphry, Sir, 1778-1829; De Quincey, Thomas, 1785-1859; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Cavendish, Georgiana Spencer, Duchess of Devonshire, 1757-1806; Dodsley, James, 1724-1797; Dorset, Thomas Sackville, Earl of, 1536-1608; Edgeworth, Maria, 1768-1849; Edwards, Thomas, 1729-1785; Everest, George, Sir, 1790-1866; Fitzgerald, Percy, 1834-1925; Fleming, Ian, 1908-1964; Fordyce, James, 1720-1796; Garrick, David, 1717-1779; Hastings, Warren, 1732-1818; Hawkins, John, 1719-1789; Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903; Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Lennox, Charlotte, approximately 1729-1804; Liebert, Herman W.; Markland, J. H. (James Heywood), 1788-1864; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; Maurice, Thomas, 1754-1824; Montolieu, Isabelle de, 1751-1832; Moore, George, 1852-1933; More, Hannah, 1745-1833; Mosby, John Singleton, 1833-1916; Mudford, William, 1782-1848; Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904; Noyes, Alfred, 1880-1958; Palgrave, Francis Turner, 1824-1897; Paoli, Pasquale, 1725-1807; Pearce, Zachary, 1690-1774; Peel, Robert, 1788-1850; Pennant, Thomas, 1726-1798; Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-1960; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903; Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744; Powys, John Cowper, 1872-1963; Pye, Henry James, 1745-1813; Romney, George, 1734-1802; Ros, Amanda McKittrick, 1860-1939; Rousseau, Jean-Jacques, 1712-1778; Sacher-Masoch, Leopold, Ritter von, 1835-1895; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864; Smith, Horace, 1779-1849; Smith, Madeleine, 1835-1928; Somerville, E. Œ. (Edith Œnone), 1858-1949; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903; Stockdale, Percival, 1736-1811; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892; Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889; Vanbrugh, John, 1664-1726; Vlaminck, Maurice de, 1876-1958; Warton, Thomas, 1728-1790; Watts-Dunton, Theodore, 1832-1914; Waugh, Evelyn, 1903-1966; Whitefoord, Caleb, 1734-1810; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wilkie, David, Sir, 1785-1841; Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850; Zamenhof, L. L. (Ludwik Lazar), 1859-1917
- Liebert Autograph Collection, Series I
  - "A"
    - Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962
      - "Ezra Pound & T. S. Eliot: A Lecture," galley proof, corrected, [1954]
    - Alexandrian Society, Inc.
      - TLS to Arthur Machen, 299 Madison Avenue, New York City, 1923 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Scope and Contents
        Signed by Boine Grainger, Secretary.
    - Empty folders
      - Empty folders (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959
      - ALS to Samuel Spewack, The Ritz-Carlton, Boston, n.d.
    - Anstey, F., 1856-1934
      - ALS to Lady Jeune, 16 Duke Street Mansions, Grosvenor Square, W., 1893 Apr 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - ALS to Dorothy, 7 York Building, Weymouth, 1895 Apr 23
      - ANS to Frederick Dolman, 16 Duke Street Mansions, Grosvenor Square, W., 1916 Jul 9
    - Aretino, Pietro, 1492-1556
      - 4 ALS (drafts) to unidentified recipients, Italy, [15--]
        On two pages.
    - Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913
      - Broadside poem, "At Naples", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        With manuscript corrections.
  - "B"
    - Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Soho Square, 1795 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Regarding Wootz and Indian drawings.
    - Baretti, Giuseppe Marco Antonio, 1719-1789
      - ALS to Hester Lynch Thrale, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
        In Italian.
    - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956
      - Zuleika Dobson, or, An Oxford Love Story, corrected proof, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Manuscript notes on Samuel Johnson, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bell, Robert, 1800-1867
      - ALS to Frederic Shoberk, Manor House, Chiswick, 1840? Dec 2? (Box 2, Folder 10)
        With envelope.
    - Boswell, James, Jr., 1778-1822
      - ALS to James Morton, London, 1794 Feb 4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Temple, 1814 Jul 5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Autograph memorandum re Burke (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Browning, Robert, 1812-1889
      - ALS to Dr. Furnivall, 19 Warwick Crescent, W., [18]86 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bruce, James, 1730-1794
      - Bruce, James. ALS to George Robinson, Kinnard, 17[89?] Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797
      - ALS to John Noble, Beaconsfield, 1781 Mar 9
        Replying to Noble's letter. Describes Burke's efforts on behalf of "the salt business."
    - Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849-1924
      - ALS to Mr. Archer, 14 Park Square East, Regents Park, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - ALS to Mrs. Lewis, 44 Lexham Gardens, South Kensington, S. W., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879
      - ALS to R. E. Lockwood, Esq., Worcester, 1841 Oct 8 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - ALS to Mrs. Goodriche, Hotel de Bavière, Hamburgh, 1850 Dec 12 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - ALS to Prof. Elton, 3 Winchester Buildings, City, 1851 Jul 15 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - ALS to Mr. Beggs, 15 New Broad Street, Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bute, John Stuart, 1st Marquess of
      - 6 ALS to Sir William Hamilton, 1764-81
        Several of the letters were written from Italy where the Marquess of Bute and James Boswell were traveling together. Accompanied by the typescript of an article by Frank Lester Pleadwell entitled "James Boswell's Maecenas on His Grand Tour."
  - "C"
    - Carter, Frederick
      - "The Old Actor", 1940 Oct 10
        Etching of Arthur Machen in proof state, with Machen's autograph.
    - Carter, John, 1905-1976
      - ALS to John Farquhar Fulton, Charles Scribner's Sons, 597 Fifth Avenue, New York, [19]35 Feb 5 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chalmers, Alexander, 1759-1834
      - ALS to Mr. J. B. Nichols, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chambers, Robert, Sir, 1737-1803
      - An epistle from R. C. to Doctor Samuel Johnson on the Choice of Life, 1766? (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Colbert, Jean Baptiste, 1619-1683
      - 6 letters to M. Daguesseau, 1675 May-Jun (Box 2, Folder 25)
        In French.
    - Cole, William, 1754-1812
      - Subscriber's receipt for "The Contradiction" signed by Cole to John Grove, Esq., 1796 Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Coleman, George
      - ALS to Richard Jones, 4 Maline Place, Wayfarers [?] Road, 1816 Jan 15 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - ALS to the manager, Olympick Theatre Royal, 1831 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir, 1845-1927
      - TLS to Mr. Freeman, 35 Palace Gardens Terrace, W. 8, 1925 Feb 21 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - ALS to John Alexander Steuart, 35 Palace Gardens Terrace, W. 8, 1925 Feb 26 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cooke, Thomas, 1703-1756
      - ALS to John Lawton, South Lambeth, 1740 Oct 28 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Autograph subscription receipt signed, 1740 Oct 28
        With printed subscription receipt dated 1739 Jul 28.
    - Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924
      - ALS to Miss Smith, 47 Longridge Road, Earl's Court, S.W., [18]88 Nov 5 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        With clipping of Corelli's obituary.
      - ALS to Mr. Sims, 47 Longridge Road, Earl's Court, S.W., [18]95 Jan 9
      - 6 ALS to Lieutenant Hobbes, Mason Croft, Stratford-on-Avon, 1914-15 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - ALS to unidentified correpondent, Mason Croft, Stratford-on-Avon, Warwickshire, 1924 Jan 22 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - ALS to the editor of Great Thoughts, Mason Croft, Stratford- on-Avon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
        With undated clipping from Great Thoughts, "Miss Corelli in Stratford-on Avon."
      - ALS to Mr. McClure, 47 Longridge Road, Earl's Court, S.W., Thurs (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Crabbe, George, 1754-1832
      - Manuscript poem (6 lines), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
        Published as part of "Tale IV, Rachel" in Posthumous Poems.
    - Crane, Walter, 1845-1915
      - ALS to Olive Molesworth, Shepherd's Bush, W., 1886 Apr 6 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878
      - ALS to M. Feuillet de Couches, London, 1847 Dec 3 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Lisbon, 1780 Jun 8 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cunninghame Graham, R. B.
      Full name: R. B. (Robert Bontine) Cunninghame Graham, 1852-1936.
      - ALS to Walter Crane, [London], 1887 Dec 1
        Mentions the right of public meeting. A test was organized by Cunninghame Graham and held in Trafalgar Square, 1887 Nov 13.
  - "D"
    - Davies, Thomas, ca. 1712-1785
      - AMS, receipt to James Dodsley, 1773 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Davy, Humphry, Sir, 1778-1829
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, 229 Piazzi Santi Apostoli, 1818 Nov 10 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        In Italian. With French translation.
    - Day, Nicholas
      - Portrait of Arthur Machen, Amersham, 1934 Mar 31
        In sepia crayon, with Machen's autograph. Original drawing for John Gawsworth's authorized life of Machen.
    - Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926
      - TLS to George Sylvester Viereck, Terre Haute, Indiana, 1925 Sep 12 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - De Quincey, Thomas, 1785-1859
      - Proof of his essay on Cicero, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
        With corrections in DeQuincey's hand.
    - De Torre, Father F. Vincentus
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Rome, [16]85 Oct 15 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Devonshire, Georgiana Spencer Cavendish, Duchess of
      Full name: Georgiana Spencer Cavendish, Duchess of Devonshire, 1757-1806.
      - AL in third person to Mr. Smith, 1799 Jul 31 (Box 2, Folder 46)
        With engraving of the Duchess published 1794 Apr 20.
    - Dodsley, James, 1724-1797
      - AL in third person to Mr. Nichols, 1795 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Dorset, Thomas Sackville, Earl of, 1536-1608
      - ANS to Sir Vincent Skinner, 1604 Feb 12 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Dowden, Edward, 1843-1913
      - ALS to Robert Browning, Cork, 1866 Feb 15
        With envelope. He questions Browning about passages in "Sordello." Accompanied by a typed copy of Browning's reply, 1866 Mar 5.
      - ALS to Professor Rudmose-Brown, Dublin, 1910 Apr 20
  - "E"
    - Edgeworth, Maria, 1767-1849
      - 3 AMS, notes on the Edgeworth family, 1836 Sep 6 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Edward VII, King of Great Britain, 1841-1910
      - Document signed, 1900 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Edwards, Thomas, 1729-1785
      - ALS to Mr. Samuel Richardson, [Lurrick?], 1753 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Everest, George, Sir, 1790-1866
      - ALS to C. Stratford, Esq., 8 Old Cavendish Street (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "F"
    - Fitzgerald, Percy Hetherington, 1834-1925
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, 67 St. Georges No, S. W., Dec 6 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Fordyce, James, 1720-1796
      - DS, order for payments to Mr. Cadell, bookseller, Putney Heath, 1778 Feb 15 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "G"
    - Garrick, David, 1717-1779
      - ALS to William Julius Mickle, 1770 May 30 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - "Epilogue" written for Arthur Murphy's Know Your Own Mind, [1777]
        Manuscript in the hand of an amanuensis, with corrections in Garrick's hand.
      - [Little Busy, Bustling Will], 1777
        Poem about William Woodfall, possibly by Garrick but in an unidentified hand and signed with Garrick's initials by Woodfall's son, Edward. Accompanied by a ribbon worn by Garrick at the Shakespeare Jubilee, Stratford, 1769, and an engraving of Garrick.
    - Garrick, Eva Maria, 1724-1822
      - AL in third person to Mr. Murphy, Adelphi, Feb 25 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911
      - ALS to [Burnand?], Graeme's Dyke, Harrow Weald, 1891 Oct 19
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928
      - ALS to John Kendrick Bangs, London, 1887 Oct 13
      - ALS to John H. Ingram, London, 1877 Jan 1
        Refers to Ingram's edition, and a portrait, of Edgar Allan Poe.
      - 2 ALS to Frank Lester Pleadwell, London, 1926, 1927
      - ALS to Grant Richards, London, 1902 Mar 19
        Marked "Private and confidential" and about an unidentified author applying for help.
      - 3 ALS to Sir Humphrey Rolleston, London, 1923-26
      - ALS to Mr. [G. M.?] Williamson, London, 1902 May 13
      - "The Pipe Player", n.d.
        Autograph manuscript sonnet, signed. Written on a sheet of letter paper watermarked 1891.
    - Gosse, Ellen, Lady
      - ALS to John Lane, London, 1894 Apr 13
        Refers to Edmund Gosse's contributions to the Yellow Book.
  - "H"
    - Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider), 1856-1925
      - ALS to William Loeb, Washington, 1905 Mar 10
        Accepting an invitation to lunch with President and Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt.
    - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928
      - ALS to Jerome K. Jerome, Max Gate, 1894 Aug 26
    - Hastings, Warren, 1732-1818
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1777 Sep 21 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Letter in third person to Mr. Scott, Park Lane, 1794 Jan 31 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Hawker, Peter, 1786-1853
      - ALS to Robert Rising, Keyhaven, 1841 Nov 7
    - Hawkesworth, John
      - ALS to John Hoole, Bronley Kent, Sun night (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hawkins, John, Sir, 1719-1789
      - ALS to John Nichols, 1787 Apr 8 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Letter in third person to John Nichols, 1787 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 61)
        In hand of Hawkins's son, John Sidney Hawkins.
    - Hawkins, Laetitia Matilda, 1760-1835
      - 2 ALS to unidentified correspondents, Twickenham (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Haydon, Benjamin Robert, 1786-1846
      - ALS to Alaric Watts, 1827 Mar 15
    - Heber, Reginald
      - ALS to J. Thornton, Esq., Hodneck Hall, Whitchurch, Shropshire, Aug 25 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - ALS to N. Wallich, Esq., M. D., Jan 6 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Hector, Edmund
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Jul 29 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903
      - ALS to Billy Heinemann, St. George's Lodge, Chesswood Road, Worthing, [18]91 Dec 26 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Herbert, William, 1771-1851
      - "Time," AMS, 1838 Jun 5 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Hill, George Birkbeck Norman, 1835-1903
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Apsley Guire, Beds, 1901 Apr 27 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Hogg, James, 1770-1835
      - ALS to Dr. J[ohn Clarke-] Whitfield, Altrive Lake by Selkirk, 1816 Jan 18
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Altrive Lake [Selkirkshire, Scotland], 1824 Jul 11
        Letter of introduction for a Mr. Emerson.
    - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859
      - Miscellaneous collection of autograph manuscripts, n.d.
        Consists of fragments of two plays and two poems, notes for essays, a brief bibliography, notes on Latin grammar and vocabulary, note to an unidentified recipient, etc.
    - Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910
      - Draft of ALS to Charles Dickens, [Letor?] Villa, Campden Hill, W., 1858 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
      - 7 ALS, 1853-75 (Box 2, Folder 70)
        Regarding scientific topics and his writing. Recipients: B. S. Baynes, A. & C. Black, John Chapman, and Admiral Fitzroy.
  - "J"
    - James, Robert
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Jerrold, Douglas William, 1803-1857
      - ALS to Dudley Costello, Putney, 1848 May 6
    - Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784
      - ALS to Edmund Hector, Gough Square, Fleet Street, 1755 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 72)
        Refers to his dictionary-making in this letter to his school mate and lifelong friend. The only letter he wrote the day his dictionary was published.
      - Letter in the hand of H. L. Piozzi to Louise Flint, 1769 Mar 31 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - ALS to Mrs. Thrale, London, 1781 Apr 5 (Box 2, Folder 74)
        Regarding the death of his friend and patron Henry Thrale.
      - Epigrammatvm graecorvm libri VII, annotationibvs Ioannis Brodaei... 1549, holograph translation into Latin of verse no. 322 by Damascius, in the hand of Samuel Johnson, [1784] (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Malos tueri haud tutum, AM, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - "Elegy on the Death of Dr. Robt. Levett by Dr. Johnson," in unknown hand (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Scrapbook containing ca. 60 engraved portraits of Johnson and some of his friends, as well views relating to him (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Johnston, Richard Malcolm, 1822-1898
      - ALS to R[ichard] W[atson] Gilder, 33 W. North Ave., 1891 Jul 29
        With clipping of portrait of Johnston.
    - Jones, A. Heywood
      - ALS to John Farnsworth, Central Library, Kensington High St., W. S., [19]33 Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Kennedy, John
      - ALS to Thomas Towers, Esq., Bradley, near Ashburn not Ashton, 1777 Dec 29 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Knowles, Mary
      - ALS to Mr. Bowyer, Chippen Warden, 74 Jun 15 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - ALS to Mr. Porter, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - "L"
    - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch, Marquis de
      Full name: Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de Lafayette, 1757-1834.
      - ALS to Elbridge Gerry, Paris, 1785 Mar 16 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Lampton, William J.
      - TLS to Mr. Crane, 1913 Mar 25
        With newspaper clipping, "At Fort Sumter in 1861" by Lampton; and printed versions of poems by Lampton: "To Whom It May Concern", "Our Air Castles", "Attention!!", and "Why a Man Likes a Dog."
    - Langton, Bennet, 1737-1801
      - End of ALS (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930
      - ALS to V. H. Collins, Villa Miranda, Scandicci, Florence, 1926 Nov 1 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Lennox, Charlotte, ca. 1729-1804
      - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1752 Mar 12 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Lincoln, Marvin
      - ALS to Mr. Oland Bourne, Boston, 1867 Mar 29 (Box 3, Folder 87)
        With ALS from Lewis A. Horton to Lincoln, 1867 Mar 21, Newburyport.
    - Long, John Luther, 1861-1927
      - ALS to [Richard Watson] Gilder, n.d.
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891
      - ALS to Mrs. Boughton, 10, Lowndes Square, S.W., 1881 Jan 25
  - "M"
    - Markland, J. H. (James Heywood), 1788-1864
      - 8 ALS, 1831-54 (Box 3, Folder 88)
        Some to J. W. Croker.
    - Masefield, John, 1878-1967
      - ALS to editor, Hampden, Missenden, Buckn., England, 1910 Aug 28 (Box 3, Folder 89)
        Regarding reprinting his poems "Roadways" and "A June Twilight."
    - Mason, William Monck, 1775-1859
      - ALS to John Wilson Croke, Recon Tower, Dublin Castle, 1830 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Maurice, Thomas, 1754-1824
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, London, British Museum, 1802 Feb 16 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      - ALS to unidentified correspondent, British Museum (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Mitford, Mary Russell, 1787-1855
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Three Mile Cross, n.d.
    - Montolieu, Isabelle de, 1751-1832
      - ANS to M. Maunvoir, [1785] (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Moore, George, 1852-1933